In this video, will develop the Viterbi algorithm in detail for this example.
在本视频中 我们将用维特比算法详细分析这个示例
And if you've seen dynamic programming,
如果你见过动态编程的话
that's exactly what we're doing.
就会完全熟悉整个流程
So here's our trellised diagram with the two probability tables, mission and transition.
这是我们的网格图 包含两个概率表 即发射概率表和转移概率表
Let's draw this a bit larger with all the probabilities.
放大这个图表 并标注所有概率
Recall that on each node we have the emission probabilities,
在每个节点上都有发射概率
so that's the probability that the particular part of speech generated the word above.
即特定词性生成上方单词的概率
And on the edges, we have the transition probabilities which are
在边缘上是转移概率
the probability that we get from one state to the next one.
即从一个状态到另一个状态的概率
For clarity, we've removed the edges that have
澄清下 我们删除了概率为零的边缘
probability zero but we still consider them.
但是依然会考虑它们
Now, the idea is that for each state or dot in the diagram,
思考方法是 对于每个状态或图表中的每个点
we will record the maximum probability of all the paths that
我们将记录在抵达该点
end in that dot and generate the words that are above.
并生成上方单词的所有路径中概率最高的路径
So let's start from the left.
从左侧开始
The probability that the word Jane is generated by the path that ends at
以顶部 N 节点结尾的路径
the top end node is the product of
生成单词 Jane 的概率是
the probability of getting to that node from the start node,
从起始节点抵达该节点的概率
which is three quarters,
（即 3/4）
times the probability that the node generated the word Jane which is two over nine.
乘以该节点生成单词 Jane 的概率 即 2/9
This product is one sixth that was recorded.
积为 1/6 记下该值
Likewise, the probability of the M node is one-quarter times zero which is
同样 M 节点的概率为 1/4 乘以 0 结果为 0
zero and the one on the V node is zero times zero which is zero.
V 节点的概率是 0*0 结果为 0
Now, let's go to the next word will.
现在转到下个单词 will
There are three paths that end in the top right N node.
有三个路径以右上角的 N 节点结尾
One coming from the previous N,
一个来自上个 N 节点
one from the previous M and one from the previous
一个来自上个 M 节点 一个来自上个 V 节点
V. We need to look at the three and pick the one with the largest probability.
我们需要查看这三个路径并选择概率最高的路径
The probability for the path coming from the N node is one-sixth,
来自 N 节点的路径概率是 1/6
which is a probability so far until the word Jane,
即目前为止抵达单词 Jane 的概率
times the transition probability one over nine to get to the new N node,
乘以转移概率 1/9 抵达新的 N 节点
times the emission probably one over nine for a emitting the word will.
乘以发射概率 1/9 生成单词 will
We'll record this product as one-sixth times one-ninth times one-ninth.
记下积 1/6*1/9*1/9
Likewise, for the path that comes from the M,
同样 对于来自 M 的路径
the probability is zero times one-quarter times one-ninth.
概率是 0*1/4*1/9
And for the path that comes from the V,
对于来自 V 的路径
it's zero times one times one-ninth.
概率是 0*1*1/9
Since two of these are zero,
因为其中两个的结果是 0
the largest one is the first one which is one over 486.
因此最大的概率是第一个路径 即 1/486
So we will record that number as the probability of
我们记下该数字
the highest probability path that ends up that point.
它是抵达该点概率最高的路径对应的概率
And this is important,
注意
of the three coming edges,
在三个传入边中
we will keep the one that gave the highest value.
我们将保留概率最高的边
So that is blue edge over here and will delete the other ones.
也就是这里的蓝边 并删除另外两个边
If two edges give us the same value, that's completely okay.
如果两个边的值完全相同 也没关系
We can break ties by picking one of them randomly.
可以随机选择一个边
Now, we'll continue this algorithm and feel free to sing along with
我们将继续利用该算法 你可以继续观看
it or pause the video if you'd like to do the calculations in detail.
或暂停视频并自己计算这些值
For the M node, the competing probabilities are
对于 M 节点 概率分别为
one-sixth times one-third times three-quarters zero and zero.
1/6*1/3*3/4 0 和 0
So the winner is the first one,
因此最大概率是第一个
which has one over 24.
结果为 1/24
Again, we keep the blue edge since they gave us the highest value.
同样保留蓝边 因为它的概率最高
For the next one, it is zero since the three of them are zero.
下个节点 结果为零 因为三个边都是零
Here we can keep pretty much any edge since they all give us the same value.
现在我们几乎可以保留任何边 因为它们的值一样
Since it's zero, in order to prevent cluttering,
因为是零 为了防止出现凌乱情况
let's actually not keep any of the edges.
我们不保留任何边
We'll continue doing this in the future when we get all zeroes.
以后 如果所有值都是零 我们将继续这么操作
And we continue over each word always calculating the three probabilities coming from
对每个单词重复这个流程 始终计算来自前面节点的三个概率
before and taking the largest one and remembering which edge gave us the largest value.
选择概率最大的路径并记下值最大的边
Keeping that one and removing the other ones.
保留该边并删除其他边
Now, we have a probabilities and also our edges that get us to those probabilities.
现在 我们获得了概率以及相应的边
So how do we get our optimal path?
如何获得最优路径呢？
Well, we'll start from the end and trace backwards.
从后往前追踪
Since each state only has one incoming edge,
因为每个状态只有一个传入边
then this should give us a path that comes all the way from the beginning.
这样就可以获得从结束一直到起始位置的路径
And that path is the winning path.
这个路径就是最优路径
This gives us the chain of states that generates the observations with
这样就可以获得生成上方观察结果
the highest probability and that's how we conclude
概率最高的一系列状态
that the most likely tags for the sentence are noun,
因此我们得出结论 这个句子最有可能的标签是
modal, verb, and noun.
名词-情态动词-动词-名词
And these are correct so I hit a mark of our modal did a great job.
这个结果是正确的 因此我们的隐马尔可夫模型效果很棒
And as you notice, we didn't need to check three to the four paths.
正如你所注意到的 我们不需要检查 3 的 4 次幂个路径
We only needed that label around the three times four nodes which is much faster.
只需检查 3*4 个节点周围的标签 这样快多了